yes I agree with that I think that's a
very good point that Anderson brought up
and thank you for pointing that out
yeah and that's interesting because and
that has to do and with you know the
degree to which we how should we take
the hero's journey within the martial
arts and I know Rafe Kelly is again
doing work on this explicitly but what
you set up what you said brings out a
really important point and that goes
towards something I've been doing quite
a bit of work on recently which is
trying to work try to build on the work
of La Paul and transformative experience
and Agnes Cal art and aspiration right
where you may think that there's there's
there's video allow me there's sort of
this way in she can frame the hero's
journey I'm going to defeat all of my
opponents I'm going to defeat all of my
peers right but there you could also
think of the hero's journey as an
aspirational one which is there's a
future self that I want to be that I'm
not currently that self right this is a
self that you know has perspectives and
virtues and prep and preferences that I
don't have this is perhaps and wiser
self or a more rational self or a more
virtuous self and that's a different
that's a different hero's journey
because now the relationship is between
your current self and your future self
and it's it's a very different thing
because the skills you need to build are
not just the skills of combat or the
skills let's call them the skills of
victory you need to but you need to
build up these important skills that
peak like I'm this agent right now in
this particular arena this is this is
who I am and this is how I see and
understand the world and I want to be
that person if you'll allow me to use
space to refer to time right I want to
be that person over there a different
person living in a different world is
why people go into therapy right they
want to be a different person and living
in a different world they want to right
and so their skills I've get the skills
of moving between worlds in this
existential sensible world are not the
same skills as combat they are not the
same skills as common you as a and I
agree with you I think you can develop
your skills of combat and be best in
that sense but if you have not engaged
in a lot of the processes that I talked
about the inactive analogy and a Gog aid
of serious play this is all in my series
for people who want to take a deeper
look at these ideas but if you don't
cultivate these skills let's call them
the skills of transformation that trans
frame you from one world to another
you can have your combat skills at a
very high level and that doesn't mean
you've aspired very much at all right so
I agree with you that if people are
trying to incorporate the hero mythos
into their martial practice they should
sit down and reflect well which way do I
want it do I want it this way like you
know I just want to be able to defeat my
contemporaries is that the hero's
journey on I'm on or is the hero's
journey right I want to I want to move
to that person in that world and then
because then what you have to do is you
have to do with what we were talking
about earlier
Dondre you have to think about
cultivating all of these other things so
you can develop the skills of
transcendence and trance framing not
just the skills of conv